Guide to the Department of Agricultural Economics Research Project Records 1911-1963
Montana State University Library, Archives and Special Collections, Manuscript Collections
- Farm Tax Data, 43
  There is no final report or authority with this data, which seems to have been gathered during the 1920s and up to about 1933. R.R. Renne was involved in at least some aspects of the data gathering, as his name appears on scattered correspondence in some of the files. Records include: Information on mill levies and taxes paid on selected property in the counties studied; correspondence relating to tax information from those counties; tabulated data regarding railroad tax monies and how they were used in selected counties. The data was originally packaged in folders divided into regions, and this separation has been roughly preserved. The original designations were Central District (there appear to have been two - one containing Fergus, Lewis & Clark, Cascade, and Petroleum counties and another containing Golden Valley and Musselshell counties), South East District (Custer and Rosebud counties), North West District (Missoula and Flathead counties), South West District (Madison, Gallatin, and Beaverhead counties), North East District (Dawson, McCone, Sheridan, and Valley counties), South Central District (Carbon, Big Horn, Sweet Grass and Yellowstone counties), and North Central District (Hill, Teton, Chouteau, and, Blaine counties). The railroad tax information is limited to 1933 and focuses mainly on its use for education.
  - Farm tax data for Central 1 District (Box 18, Folder 8-11)
  - Farm tax data for South East District (Box 18, Folder 12-13)
  - Farm tax data for North West District (Box 18, Folder 14-15)
  - Farm tax data for South West District (Box 18, Folder 16-18)
  - Farm tax data for North East District (Box 18, Folder 19-22)
  - Farm tax data for South Central District (Box 18, Folder 23-26)
  - Farm tax data for North Central District (Box 18, Folder 27-30)
  - Farm tax data for Central 2 District (Box 18, Folder 31-32)
  - Railroad tax use data - apparently compiled by R. Renne (Box 18, Folder 33)
- Foreclosure Data, 1900-1936; 44
  This series consists of cards recording farm foreclosure information for a number of Montana counties from about 1900 through 1936. The period covered seems to depend on the county being surveyed. Most of the cards contain notes, and some even show that they have been researched a second and third time. However, there is no indication in this series as to what this data was used for. It is possibly the original source data for the reports contained in Series 32, although the periods being studied do not match and there is no correspondence or other information to back up this assumption. There is also a discrepancy between the counties used in the Series 32 study and the counties with completed cards in this Series. In all, fourteen counties were studied, with a number of reclassifications being done. The final folders contain tabulated data on all bankruptcies and foreclosures of Montana farms between 1898 and 1937.
  - Beaverhead County (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Big Horn County (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Blaine County (Box 19, Folder 3-7)
  - Broadwater County (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Daniels County (Box 19, Folder 9-10)
  - Dawson County (Box 19, Folder 11-12)
  - Deer Lodge County (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Fallon County (Box 19, Folder 14-15)
  - Flathead County (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Hill County (Box 19, Folder 17-18)
  - Jefferson County (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Judith Basin County (Box 20, Folder 1-3)
  - Lake County (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Missoula County (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Rough and final copies of the bankruptcy data for all Montana counties, 1898-1937 (Box 20, Folder 6-9)
  - Miscellaneous data, likely unrelated to the other material in this series (Box 20, Folder 10-11)